George and Sean right here to your left.
Can you tell us what uh what stood out
about Tyler Onettum uh and what he
brings to this defensive line this year
and moving forward?
>> Yeah, I mean I think going through this
process it was really the athleticism,
you know, when playing a position that
it's always hard to find defensive
tackle. Um
I mean his strike, his shed. Um but it
was it was the athlete makeup. Um those
were the those were the traits.
Uh Chris Thomas in Denver Gazette. Sean,
do you see him as a guy who potentially
could compete for the position vacated
by by John Franklin Myers?
>> Yeah. And um definitely, you know, when
when we're taking a player in that spot,
um we discuss vision all the time. So,
um yeah, absolutely. Um they're going to
come in, earn their um you know, earn
their place, but um we would We go
through this this all the time after the
read um Broncos vision year one. Um and
it's it was it was positive, you know,
not only with the scouts but the coaches
as well.
>> Uh for both of you, what was it like? I
mean, you you've had the long wait
before before your first pick, I guess,
moving back and then also watching
through the sort of middle of the second
round there. A lot of linebackers, a lot
of tight ends. Just watching that run
through the middle of the second round.
I mean, it's a typical draft. I mean,
there was a run, you know, in certain
positions as we figured they would be. I
mean, it it fell like we thought it
would. You know, I think I mentioned we
had six players and and um you know, it
it just they all started going, you
know, the six and and uh Tyler was one
of the six, but it um it felt kind of
like we thought it would. And uh I mean
you know yesterday as you mentioned it
was that's a boring day but you know we
we forget we did trade for one of the
better receivers in the league. So it
was it was a good day you know.
>> Yes. With with respect to the uh this
fine defensive lineman. I think there
was hope maybe belief that there would
be a little more splash on the offensive
side. How close were you to maybe adding
another weapon uh as you went into this
uh day?
Well, I I think you go into the day and,
you know, we're we're looking closely at
the grade and and the stack and um you
know, we're never trying to worry about
the splash. Um we're really trying to
look at it with the proper vision, the
proper grade and um so
yeah, were there offensive players,
defensive players, you're following that
and then um
you know it was pretty clear without um
trying to reach maybe for another
position. Um, so that I mean it there
there at that pick and then our wiggle
back um made complete sense and uh so I
don't think there was this
either or it was pretty clear where he
sat with his grade um versus the field
and and that's you know being smart to
the board. Coach, when you got here,
added McGllinchi, you added Zack Allen
built at the line of scrimmage. I guess
how reflective is this pick of just
continuing that kind of desire to win up
front, win at the line of scrimmage?
>> Yeah, they're all they're always, you
know, when the season ends and and you
begin to look at free agency, there's
certain positions that are just harder
to find. Um, and
you know
when you when you look at a roster that
it could have been offensive line at the
right position. It could have been a few
other pos, you know, positions, but um
it's harder to find those D lineman and
offensive linemen. You know, when the
when the window of free agency begins,
they're they're valued. They're hard.
for both of you. Uh Tyler mentioned his
conversations with uh Coach Kaine about
uh just getting to know him. So what did
Jamar kind of convey to you about what
he learned about Tyler in the course of
this process? Well, I I mean I think
there's a series of postseason, call it
spring checks, combine visits, learning
all those were extremely positive and
and uh and very important to the
process, you know, Bronco Fit. Um so I
think our scouting staff, all the guys
that work on it have a really good
vision as to maybe what our team is
expecting as well.
um sitting here in 2026
regarding makeup and um toughness. So,
um, and it, you know, it was Jamar, but
man, there's area scouts, cross check
scouts, there there's so much that goes
in there. You know, when the process
ends, how many reports total? I mean,
there'd be 8 to 10 um, conservatively.
and and then the board set and then you
know there's with this pick
I mean I I felt like together
um for the last call it 3 weeks month um
that group of six seven eight players
the amount of film that you continue to
challenge yourself with um so you feel
like you really know
exactly the vision and and the traits Um
because look, if you're picking at 14 or
15, there's a two or three player spray
or dispersion
and you back it up a little bit and then
you know gets a little wider, but we
were a week ahead I felt like and um
there was a lot of film on on him watch.
>> When you get to go into a day three and
you have have seven picks, what what do
you kind of like about that that
position that that you're in and what
you're able to accomplish? We're in a
good position especially with the two we
have you know the seventh pick and the
fourth round and the 11th I believe you
407 411 and so you started with that and
then you can just you know we've gone
through all these you know third days we
like we're a week ahead so we already
know the scenarios we're in for starting
with these first two and that kind of
sets the tone and Sean and I have always
you know as we go through our
discussions these two fourth round picks
will define this draft you know we we
should if we're doing you doing our job
we should hit on the or the third now
third round pick, but really these it's
uh the middle picks, you know, that
really define your draft and especially
because we're picking up, you know, in
the fourth up high
>> over to your right. Just on Tyler
specifically, did he show you sort of an
expanded portfolio at Texas A&M uh over
what he his role was at Iowa State?
>> Yeah, Jeeoff, good question. I mean,
Iowa State, they were playing him in a
different, you know, it was a 335
scheme. He was two block two gapping,
you know, playing blocks. He wasn't
penetrating, wasn't rushing as much. You
got to see him do that more at&m, which
he'll be doing here. And so the tape, we
like, you know, the tape was good at
Iowa State. We really liked it at&m.
>> That that that defensive scheme
sometimes, that's one of the challenges,
too, projecting, but the importance of
him at the&m
exposure. Um, really you you you got to
see a guy
really play a different position or
technique and I I think um that probably
helped a lot of teams, not just us.
>> Yeah.
>> Hey uh George and and Sean both um can
you talk about his character uh your
draft pick and and how he fits in uh you
know he's not a guy who chases sacks and
he's sort of a team team oriented guy.
Yeah, it's it's one of the things I I
think we were just talking about. um you
know as as you
begin to procure talent into a roster
that we have into a culture that we have
um it's it's it's it's very important
and um you know sometimes
I think the current environment today um
and I'm talking about college football
um you know there's there's a lot been
discussed about NIL portal
Um and oh eligibility, you know, we're
kind of past the co after this year. Um
but that current environment
almost adds a couple test tubes to the
um
to the benefit of clubs, I think,
relative to um how they handle
um maybe money that they weren't
normally how they handle the process. um
you know whether it's transferring um
there's just a little bit more available
and I would say we probably had maybe
more in the box category than um two
years ago that uh and I think you're
getting more opportunities to evaluate
behavior.
>> Sean, when you look at your roster now,
I mean there's very few if any starting
positions open. It's a byproduct of
winning. Does that change how you look
at the draft in terms of it seems like
it would be difficult in other words for
seven or eight guys to make this team
the way you're constructed. Does that
change how you would approach this last
day where hey we might move up and get
one piece instead of three because those
guys might end up on the practice squad.
They're just not good enough to crack.
>> Look, you you always have vision forward
or backwards. You're mindful of picks.
It's it's ammunition. Um, and I think
we've talked about this a bunch during
the month of um,
you know, where are the, you know, I'll
say all the time if if I'm playing this
position, um, this is a club I want to
go to and I won't get into those
positions where maybe the vision's clear
um, and some positions it it might be
more difficult. So, um, yeah, all of
that is is factored in, you know,
tomorrow,
hour, you know, hour and a half, two
hours even before we get started. You
know, you can remock, you can you can
really talk about targets and yet
um, you got to pay close attention to
the great.
>> I just to add on to that, I mean, the
reason we've been so good the last
couple years is because of our depth.
And so where you get that depth is the
third day. And they may be backups year
one like Nick Bonito, Riley Moss, and
then year two if you hit on them, you
know, maybe you get a starter, maybe you
get a key contributor. And so that's
what we're looking for day three.
George, uh, going off of that, when you
look at potential just kind of positions
of of need, you know, depth, tight end,
linebacker, running back, did you guys
feel confident in what was going to be
there, you know, day three, fourth round
potentially to to not kind of jump back
up into the third? What was the
evaluation process there?
>> We do we like we like day three, you
know, we like where we're picking in day
three. Um, again, we're we're looking
for backup. You know, we're looking for
young developmental backups with some
traits that we can develop and and we
can find those all across day three. You
know, we're not we're not going to,
you know, reach to go up to get a guy
that, you know, so feel good with where
we're at. We feel really good about the
day. Um, feel good about the first day.
We got Vaddle and then we got this kid
that we really like and then tomorrow
we're going to have a good day.